<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-13T22:10:27-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Suhan Kacholia</title><entry><title type="html">Who Does AI Help?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/29/welcome-to-my-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who Does AI Help?" /><published>2023-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/29/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/07/29/welcome-to-my-blog/"><![CDATA[<p>Without glasses, I would be useless. My eyesight is atrocious—absent my thick lenses, the world appears a blurry, Impressionist fog. I sometimes imagine what role I would play in ancient human societies. I’m skinny, clumsy, and have poor coordination. Clearly, I’m not built for labor. The human spirit is indomitable, and I’m sure I’d find ways to muddle through. But unlike my vision, one thing is clear: I would not be where I am today if not for glasses.<br /></p>

<p>Success is contextual and ecological. No trait is intrinsically valuable. Even what we now call mental disorders likely <a href="https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-evolution-of-psychiatry">played important evolutionary roles</a>. Many individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder have <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2677593/">above-average memory, perception, and attention</a>, and autistic people may have invented technologies like “oil lamps, multi-component tools, star maps, grinding stones and fire hearths.” ADHD, by causing “impulsiveness, hyperactivity and transient concentration,” might have <a href="https://www.longdom.org/open-access/hunters-in-a-farmers-world-adhd-and-hunter-gatherers-2332-0915-1000150.pdf">helped hunter-gatherers survive their constantly shifting, hostile environments</a>. This is the basis for the neurodiversity movement: what society considers deficits are often just <em>differences</em>, and in certain environments, are strengths.</p>

<p>“Every technology has winners and losers,” writes Neil Postman in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/79678.Technopoly"><em>Technopoly</em></a>. The printing press helped Martin Luther spread the religion that now bears his name, but devalued the centralized authority of the Catholic Church. Tiny semiconductor chips enabled STEM-obsessed nerds to become billionaires, but hurt jocks: while aggression and physical strength helped our early ancestors hunt and fight, these traits are less useful for writing backend code.</p>

<p>More than any other technology, artificial intelligence (AI) will shape today. As such, it is worth asking: what <em>kind</em> of person will succeed because of AI?</p>

<p>I’ll focus here on the impacts of generative AI, like GPT and DALL-E. I’ll also focus on <em>comparative</em> advantage, relative to the status quo. For instance, while both people with coding skills and without are better off because of GPT making coding easier, I think people without coding skills have a higher <em>comparative</em> benefit from GPT by gaining an entire new skill without having spent years acquiring that skill.</p>

<p><strong>Generalists</strong><br />
I believe generalists gain a comparative edge from AI.</p>

<p>To specialize in something is a bet. The upside potential is the benefit you gain by having a well-developed and rare skill. However, there is also a downside risk if that skill you devoted yourself to becomes less valuable. Because of this, generalists are more automation-proof. Predicting AI progress is hard—you could spend years specializing in, say, predicting protein structures, until one day, a computer does the same thing with near-perfect accuracy. Few predicted how good GPT-4 would be at doing highly skilled, white-collar jobs. Being a generalist is investing in a diversified skill portfolio, hedging against automation.</p>

<p>A second reason generalists are better off is because I think we’re headed towards what I’ll call an “Editor Economy.” In my experience, for tasks beyond a low degree of complexity, GPT usually gets you <em>most</em> of the way there, but rarely <em>all</em> the way there. Reliability will improve as models improve—GPT-4 is miles better than GPT-3.5, for instance—but I doubt that AI will achieve perfection, most of the time. This means, at least in the near future, human oversight of AI output will remain necessary to tie up loose ends, if nothing else. Everyone will be an editor of sorts.</p>

<p>However, to edit requires at least some basic knowledge of the task you are editing. I think this means a “jack of all trades” could benefit more from AI tools compared to “spiky” experts. At my university, you can major in Computer Science, or you can take a mix of computer science and philosophy classes and major in Cognitive Science. I know many CompSci majors who are excellent at coding, but terrible at writing. I also know CogSci majors who are good writers and decent, but not excellent, coders.</p>

<p>If GPT makes a coding error, both majors might find the troubleshooting process equally challenging, given that the majority of the code will likely be fine. However, to edit a GPT-produced text, the CompSci major might struggle compared to the CogSci major. In an Editor Economy, a generalist is better off, more able to refine diverse AI outputs for that last mile.</p>

<p><strong>People With Good Taste</strong><br />
DALL-E and Midjourney have reduced the cost of creating beautiful art to near zero. Despite this, in my opinion, most of the AI-generated art I see online is still… mid. I don’t think this is a limitation of the technology. Rather, it signals a lack of taste.</p>

<p>Visakan Veerasamy has an excellent <a href="https://visakanv.com/taste/">essay</a> about taste, calling it the “beating heart of all creative value.” He quotes talented people, from Quentin Tarantino, to Paul Graham, to Dorothy Parker, who identify good taste as necessary to excellence in their respective field. But taste is not enough—it usually “has to be coupled with ability of some kind.” As Ira Glass <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/309485-nobody-tells-this-to-people-who-are-beginners-i-wish">discusses</a>, creative frustration occurs when there is a gap between one’s ability and one’s taste.</p>

<p>Technology narrows the gap. Before the camera, producing a realistic capture of a moment required expert painting ability. After, just a shutter click. Images proliferated after photography, but even now, <em>incredible</em> images remain rare. This is because photography unavoidably involves taste. As Susan Sontag <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52372.On_Photography">writes</a>, “Even when photographers are most concerned with mirroring reality, they are still haunted by tacit imperatives of taste and conscience.” And good taste remains scarce.</p>

<p>Music production also illustrates this well. Because of software like Ableton or Garageband, anyone can create music, without even knowing what a chord is. Hip-hop producers regularly compose beautiful, virtuosic musical collages, purely by sampling, mixing, and chopping others’ sounds. <br />
AI enables anyone to become an artist, writer, web designer, storybook illustrator, and more. As the cost of production decreases, and as the amount of <em>content</em> converges to infinity, curation and taste become ever more valuable.</p>

<p><strong>Some Personality Traits</strong><br />
Psychologists usually measure personality in terms of the Big 5 Factors:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Openness (creativity and willingness to try new things),</li>
  <li>Conscientiousness (organization and dependability),</li>
  <li>Extraversion (sociability and enthusiasm),</li>
  <li>Agreeableness (friendliness and cooperation), and</li>
  <li>Neuroticism (emotional instability and anxiety)</li>
</ul>

<p>Again, none of these traits are <em>inherently</em> good or bad—but still, in general, certain traits are more conducive towards success in the modern economy compared to others. A <a href="https://www.econstor.eu/bitstream/10419/236201/1/GLO-DP-0902.pdf">2021 meta-analysis</a> suggests that Openness, Conscientiousness, and Extraversion are positively associated with higher earnings, while Agreeableness and Neuroticism are negatively associated. This research is correlational and not causal, and the relationships are nuanced. Still, the bigger picture makes intuitive sense. In highly-paid sectors where creativity is prized, like tech, openness is a valuable trait. Conscientiousness, meanwhile, enables individuals to obtain good grades and do diligent work. Neuroticism, linked to anxiety and low self-confidence, is less helpful.</p>

<p>I predict that trait Openness will become even more of a useful personality trait for the AI age. First, technological progress is moving fast, and keeping up with change is easier if you are more interested in new ideas. Second, trait Openness is linked to creativity and intellectual breadth, which is even more useful because of generative AI, for reasons already discussed.</p>

<p>I think conscientiousness, meanwhile, is comparatively <em>less</em> useful now. Discipline is still important for accomplishing long-term goals, of course, but a lazy person can accomplish far more now. Executing projects is easier and quicker, as is learning about new topics. I am not a terribly conscientious person, but AI has made me far more productive.</p>

<p>I am not sure how the other personality traits will interact with AI, if at all. Maybe having AI write your emails in a friendly tone can compensate for low agreeableness? Maybe the relative ease of starting a solo business today will allow more introverted people to succeed? Maybe AI therapy works well, and neurotic people thrive better? I really don’t know.</p>

<p><strong>People With ADHD</strong> <br />
I think people with ADHD possess a unique combination of traits that synergize unusually well with AI tools.</p>

<p>ADHD has many downsides. It causes distractibility, lack of focus, difficulties with organization, and more. But AI tools can compensate for many of these downsides. I regularly use GPT to create schedules and to-do lists, combat the blank page problem and <a href="https://add.org/adhd-paralysis">“ADHD paralysis,”</a> and automate tedious tasks. I’m not alone: the internet abounds with <a href="https://mashable.com/article/chatgpt-ai-and-adhd">examples</a> <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/views/2023/03/01/chatgpt-can-help-students-and-faculty-adhd-opinion">of</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OpenAI/comments/103q6vf/as_someone_with_adhd_chatgpt_has_made_me_a_better/">people</a> using GPT to manage ADHD.</p>

<p>AI also harnesses the positive traits of ADHD. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33035524/">Some studies</a> indicate ADHD is linked to divergent thinking and creative ability. People with ADHD often find themselves overflowing with ideas, but lacking the focus or time to complete all of them.</p>

<p>The bottleneck used to be execution. Ideas are plenty, but implementing those ideas is the difficult part. AI has made execution easier. In <a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/superhuman-what-can-ai-do-in-30-minutes">an experiment</a>, Ethan Mollick tried to see how far he could go with a business idea in 30 minutes using AI. In the end, it “did market research, created a positioning document, wrote an email campaign, created a website, created a logo and ‘hero shot’ graphic, made a social media campaign for multiple platforms, and scripted and created a video.” This usually would have usually taken hours, if not days, requiring multiple skills and forms of expertise. Implementation is still hard, and Mollick would have to edit those imperfect outputs for any real world use. But with AI, the bottleneck is shifting from <strong><em>implementation</em></strong> to <strong><em>ideas</em></strong>.</p>

<p>This helps people with ADHD, who can turn more ideas into reality and engage different skills in short time periods. I don’t mean to paint ADHD with a broad brush here, or deny the negative, sometimes debilitating, effects it can have on people’s lives. But I do think it could empower many with the condition to live more fulfilling lives.</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong><br />
Predicting technological progress is hard, and predicting downstream effects is even harder. This list is obviously not meant to be exhaustive, and just represents my initial thoughts on who might succeed because of AI. However, I do believe it is likely that an AI-driven world will value creativity, breadth, and individuality even more. (Unless, of course, it causes extinction).</p>

<p>But regardless of who AI ends up benefiting, my broader point remains true. There are no dispositions or skills that are inherently “better” than others; there are no <em>humans</em> who are inherently “better” than others. I hope AI expands the boundaries of our world, enabling more paths for more kinds of people to succeed and create beautiful, interesting, and human things.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Without glasses, I would be useless. My eyesight is atrocious—absent my thick lenses, the world appears a blurry, Impressionist fog. I sometimes imagine what role I would play in ancient human societies. I’m skinny, clumsy, and have poor coordination. Clearly, I’m not built for labor. The human spirit is indomitable, and I’m sure I’d find ways to muddle through. But unlike my vision, one thing is clear: I would not be where I am today if not for glasses.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflections on Arizona</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/11/09/reflections-on-az/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflections on Arizona" /><published>2021-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/11/09/reflections-on-az</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/11/09/reflections-on-az/"><![CDATA[<p>Often, the absence of something reveals its most essential qualities. Leaving Arizona for college in Georgia, I learned more about my home state in three months than I had in eighteen years living there. Coming home for winter break, Arizona’s paradoxes and absurdities, its underlying schisms and all-encompassing emptiness, became inescapable to me.</p>

<p>Arizona is a tonal center for my family. We move around scales, play dissonant chords and fourths and fifths, but ultimately must resolve back home. Everyone contains a personal black hole, a place or person or thing that exerts a gravitational pull, where we return to over and over. For my family, Arizona is that black hole. My parents are from India, and moved to Arizona in 2005, when I was two. Since then, we lived in short stints everywhere from Washington, D.C. to North Carolina to Hyderabad, forced to move often because of visa issues and job changes. But somehow, by pure chance, the moves have always been temporary, eventually forcing us back to the Phoenix metropolitan area. This is ironic, because Arizona suits no one in my family. My dad and brother are both aquaphiles. My dad becomes ecstatic when seeing a river or lake on road trips, and my brother’s favorite hobby is swimming. Yet, we live in the driest state. My mother belongs somewhere like California, where she may do yoga outside and go on walks and look at flowers, instead of being stuck inside for two to four months a year. They constantly discuss moving, but inertia, in combination with some invisible attachment to the place, always prevents them.</p>

<p>In 2020, Arizona flipped from red to blue. We made national headlines; election analysts attributed the shift to the growth of Arizona’s suburbs, which now lean Democratic. Only two months later, my state featured in the news again, as an Arizonan man named Jacob Chansley, also known as “QAnon Shaman,” stormed the United States Capitol building, shirtless and adorning a viking hat.</p>

<p>Arizona is in constant tension. One impulse pulls us towards normality; towards the moderate, establishment respectability that binds together figures like John McCain and Mark Kelly. Another impulse engenders the fringe, the occult, and bizarre; the conspiracy theorists and wackos, exemplified by Chansley, young Kyrsten Sinema, and Sedona’s vortex spots. The former impulse hates extremes and adores the center, which is why Martha McSally, who spoke incessantly about the ‘radical Left’ and endorsed Trump’s wall, lost twice. The impulse towards normality is gaining power, at the expense of our oddity. This is why I think Sinema will lose in 2024. Her 2018 campaign emphasized how <em>boring</em> she was, how she had changed from her tutu-wearing past into a mature adult who spoke about healthcare and taxes. But as she gains attention in the media, for her odd outfits and even odder vote choices, it becomes evident that her past never really left. And I think Arizona will punish her for this—for all her moderation in policy, what Arizona really craves is to starve its weird half of oxygen. But Democrats need not fret; the state-level GOP, with its exemplary figures of Paul Gosar, Andy Biggs, and Kelli Ward, faces a daunting path forward for similar reasons.</p>

<p>I am an obedient liberal, and I despise the cultural and political rot represented by extremist movements like QAnon and Trumpism. And yet, in a strange way, a small part of me cannot help but lament as I see Arizona’s hegemonic suburb-liberalism snuff out our homegrown radicals. I do not harbor any sympathy whatsoever for the actual politics of those individuals; rather, I wish Arizonan idiosyncrasy manifest itself in more healthy ways. Despite what the news may portray, crazed buffoons trying to steal elections do not control our politics, though we should remain vigilant of their threat. Rather, our politics submit to polo-shirt-wearing forty-year olds who moved from California because the taxes are too high and have two kids and a dog and live in rows and rows of identical cookie-cutter homes. And this is a depressing fact.</p>

<p>The very existence of Phoenix reveals its inherent contradictions. There is no reason a city like this, with highways and golf courses and thousand-square-feet lawns, should exist in such an unforgiving desert. We imagine ourselves to be like every other city, we aspire to be like every other city, but ignore the alien landscape we live in. The warming climate threatens this purposeful obliviousness; eventually, 140 degree temperatures will prevent us from outrunning Nature and reality. But for now, we may continue to play-act and shape the environment to our conformist wants, instead of acceding to the will of the desert. One may easily imagine a different Phoenix. A Phoenix with density instead of sprawl. With respect towards water and the desert landscape, instead of wastefulness. With unique, experimental, but forward-facing, politics, forged from our unique, experimental context, instead of the binary options of milquetoast liberalism and batshit craziness.</p>

<p>A friend of mine is into movies. Out of boredom, we once played a game where I would name a state and he would attempt to offer a film or show set there. I tried to stump him, to no avail. Arkansas? <em>Minari</em>. Vermont? <em>Dead Poets Society</em>. Even Idaho has <em>Napoleon Dynamite</em>. But then I asked about Arizona. He contemplated for a moment, and then answered, “That scene in <em>Arrested Development</em> where Michael decides to move to Phoenix, but then immediately leaves because the airport taxi door-handle is too hot.”</p>

<p>There are no Arizonan stereotypes. In contrast, our next-door neighbor, California, occupies a sprawling empire in the American mythology. It is a mystical land of douchebag skaters and vegan stoners, of pungent hippies and egotistic entrepreneurs, of Valley girls and Bernie Bros. Utah has its Mormons and skiers; Colorado, granola types and fitness freaks. But Arizona? We represent an abyss, an imaginatory void. Arizonans do not possess any accent; we lack the <em>y’alls</em> and <em>ain’t</em> sprinkled in Southern speak. Ohio is known for being boring, but at least it’s known for <em>something</em>. But in a way, Arizona’s cultural vacuity is positive. When I tell people where I’m from, they fail to find any preconception to attach to me. Their minds search desperately for a joke or witty remark to make—something like the “Oh, you must be a hipster” that Oregonians get, or the corn jokes Iowans despise—but ultimately, they find nothing to say, besides “It sure gets hot there!” And so, I remain a <em>tabula rasa</em>, freed from the oppressive baggage of background.</p>

<p>In early 2021, Arizona’s basketball team, the Phoenix Suns, reached the NBA finals. Arizona’s sports teams are usually uniformly terrible, so this marked a notable event. I am not a fan of sports by any means. I do not understand the rules of football or baseball, and generally scorned the perceived obnoxiousness of sports fans. However, during that NBA season, I unashamedly joined the bandwagon. I watched every finals game, often at bars or restaurants with my friends, and even went to the stadium to watch a televised away game. And it was incredible. The Suns provided a locus to “rally the valley,” giving a sense of community, fraternity, and shared purpose to the Phoenix metropolitan area. And it helped me feel like I actually lived somewhere: a living, specific location with actual characteristics. I felt, perhaps for the first time, pride in a place. This feeling is probably common to regular sports enthusiasts, but the Suns’ historic run expanded the boundaries of that experience beyond that limited social bubble. And though the Suns lost and the feeling eventually dissipated, the warm embers of that pride remained for some time.</p>

<p>In Arizona, I lived in the city of Chandler. Like all Phoenix suburbs, the population of Chandler, Arizona rose dramatically in recent decades. In 1980, the city contained less than 30,000 people; now, the population is around 270,000. Historically, Chandler’s main industries included agriculture and ranching. Today, its top employers include Intel and Wells Fargo. Chandler is a liminal space, resting in the space between modernity and history, urbanization and agrarianism. Mornings before high school, I would gaze upon the vast green landscape of the alfalfa farm across from my house, the stench of cow manure wafting through the air. Only moments later, I would pass Price Corridor, a massive complex of multistory office buildings. Google’s Waymo division selected Chandler as its first test site for autonomous vehicles. And so, Chandler is perhaps the only place in the world where it is commonplace to see a driverless car next to someone riding a horse.</p>

<p>As Chandler grows, the alfalfa farms and cattle ranches and horse stables shrink further into the margins. We march towards the homogeneous non-place that is American suburbia; one day, we will become indistinguishable from the Alpharettas and Edisons and Evanstons of the world. Luckily, we contain enough weirdness to stave off this inevitability for at least some time. Chandler hosts an “Ostrich Festival” every year, inspired by Chandler’s early history of ostrich farming. Even as the festival grows more and more commercialized and similar to any other carnival every year, it is still pretty fucking weird that we have an annual event dedicated to ostriches. Every Christmas, Chandler lights a large Christmas tree made of tumbleweeds, complete with a parade. We have a park that used to be a working landfill; the city simply covered it with rocks to hide its shameful past.</p>

<p>The cultural center of my town is probably the mall, named Chandler Fashion Mall. We lack the agora of ancient Athens; we must settle instead for Panda Express and H\&amp;M. The mall is where teenagers and adults alike gather, shop, and bond. The mall encloses my most formative memories. It is where my friends and I made immature jokes in the Spencer’s store and spilled secrets in the Starbucks; it is where we watched a mother drag her crying child, who left poop stains on the linoleum floor, and where my once-closest friend came out to me. I imagine the mall serves as a similar purpose for other Chandler denizens.</p>

<p>The mall was also my personal cultural center, for a very different reason. As this piece repeatedly implies, the Phoenix suburbs are, by and large, a cultural vacuum. And how I desired culture! Throughout high school, I craved desperately to live somewhere like New York City or San Francisco, where I imagined I could cultivate a sophisticated taste in art and architecture and music; I longed to be inundated by culture, wanted culture left and right and up and down. But I lived in Chandler, and so I made do. Inside Chandler Fashion Mall exists a franchise of Barnes and Noble. And this is where I’d spent many of my weekends, sipping on the intoxicating words of Dostoevsky and Orwell to escape the perceived superficiality of the world outside.</p>

<p>I do not mean to sound like I am complaining. In fact, I am actually glad for Chandler’s lack of cultural refinement. I appreciate its various aesthetic travesties, appreciate its homogeneously hideous houses and drab dirt lots. Because Chandler forced me to find beauty wherever I could find it. In printed words on a page, in a pastel-pink sunset, in a cactus flower in full bloom. And only the suburban part of suburban Arizona is ugly. You need only to venture a few miles out from the islands of indistinguishable houses and strip malls before encountering Arizona’s saving grace, its natural beauty. What we lack in culture, we make up for in mountain peaks and stately saguaros, otherworldly ocotillos and the sublime.</p>

<p>My new home of Athens, Georgia hosts an annual event called PorchFest. Neighborhood residents lend their porches to local musicians, who play for free for anyone who walks by. To me, this represents the ideal urban innovation. PorchFest fosters community, bringing together residents and students outdoors for a day dedicated to sharing music. It highlights Athens’ dynamic music scene and facilitates the discovery of local artists. PorchFest might work in Flagstaff, Arizona’s analogue to Athens, or maybe Sedona. But it could never work in Phoenix. For starters, most of us lack porches. Beyond that, however, Phoenix is too spread out, its neighborhoods too replete with isolated boxes, for PorchFest to work. But there is no reason we cannot invent creations like PorchFest of our own, tailored to the specifics of our home. And there is no reason we cannot chart a new course for Phoenix, a desert urbanism centered around community and connection.</p>

<p>Last summer, the summer before college, I explored Phoenix more than I ever had growing up. Emboldened by the possession of a car and free time, I exhausted the city of its nooks and crannies. I attended open mic nights and improv shows with friends, I made repeat visits to the Phoenix Art Museum and the Desert Botanical Gardens, and I ate at the most interesting restaurants I could find. The Perch in Chandler, which also functions as a rescued bird sanctuary; Otro Cafe, which made some of the best vegan Mexican food I’ve ever had. I sampled Phoenix’s best ice cream, including Novel Ice Cream in Midtown, which makes ice cream sandwiches with donuts, and Sweet Republic, whose mint ice cream tasted like actual mint and not toothpaste. Beyond the beige buildings and lifeless freeways, Phoenix contains a soul.</p>

<p>Arizona is, in many respects, undefinable. I focused here mostly on the Phoenix metropolitan area because that is what I am most familiar with, but Arizona contains staggering multitudes. The north ripples with forests, the Grand Canyon, and the mesmeric red rocks of Sedona. The desolate beauty of deserts defines the rest of the state. I bemoan Phoenix’s lack of culture in this piece, but perhaps this is because our metropolis is one of diaspora. No one has been here for long, from the Sudanese refugees to the Californians to my Indian-American parents. We are all still figuring this strange, paradoxical place out. And perhaps there is a beauty in being somewhere empty. Perhaps there is beauty in watching a culture grow, and contributing—in our small, miniscule ways—to that fledgling seed we call a home.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Often, the absence of something reveals its most essential qualities. Leaving Arizona for college in Georgia, I learned more about my home state in three months than I had in eighteen years living there. Coming home for winter break, Arizona’s paradoxes and absurdities, its underlying schisms and all-encompassing emptiness, became inescapable to me.]]></summary></entry></feed>